ILGWU. Cleveland Joint Board records 5780/048
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Cleveland Joint Board records
1934-1959
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cleveland Joint Board
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/048
3.5 cubic feet
3.5 linear ft.
Minutes.
Contains correspondence, memoranda, printed material on companies and local unions throughout Ohio, and files on the Los Angeles Joint Board and Philadelphia Joint Board. Also included are files on several Cleveland locals (26, 29, 37, 42, 63, 200, 207, 211), as well as locals in Toledo (67, 368, 466), and Conneaut (175).
5490712
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 24, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 16, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
Cleveland had a garment industry very early on, in fact, a Cloak Pressers' Protective Union was formed in 1899, before the founding of the ILGWU. The early Cleveland Joint Board consisted of Cloak and Suit Tailors 26, Skirt and Dress Makers 27, Women Garment Makers 29, Ladies' Garment Pressers 37, Ladies' Garment Cutters 42, Sample and Ladies Tailors 94.
Strikes and low membership decimated the union in Cleveland from the strike of 1911 until the near closure of the Joint Board in 1916. The union had a difficult time gaining a position in the cloak and suit trade of the city. By the summer of 1917, membership in the Joint Board had risen significantly and in 1918, the union and the Joint Board submitted demands to the Cleveland Garment Manufacturers' Association for a wage increase. After a strike, a Board of Referees was established to hear the controversy and render decisions. Relations between manufacturers and the Joint Board were strained, but in 1919, a collective agreement was signed by the manufacturers' associations and the Cleveland Joint Board finally and firmly establishing the union in Cleveland after a decade of struggle. During this time, Charles Kreindler was the manager of the Joint Board.
In the 1920s, Cleveland was one of the only large cities that did not subscribe to a 44 hour week and week-work in the garment industry. Instead, the shops that manufactured medium priced garments utilized the section system, which required less skilled labor and posed a challenge for the Cleveland cloakmakers. An investigation by Cleveland Joint Board and the Cloak Manufacturers' Association established standards of production. In 1932, there was the Cleveland Cloak and Dress Strike. Hearings were conducted in 1938 before an impartial chairman to eliminate differences between the New York and Cleveland Cloak markets. By 1944, the Joint Board had established vacations with pay for all garment workers in the market, as well as adding a health plan with medical care, sick benefits and life insurance. The Joint Board was comprised of Locals 26, 27, 29, 37, 42, 44, 52, 207, 209, 211, 300, 358, and 368. The Joint Board and Ohio district were headed by Abraham Katovsky, who had been a business agent under Kreindler, and helmed the Cleveland Joint Board until his death in 1945. He was succeeded by Nathan Solomon as the new manager. Solomon had been serving as the secretary treasurer for many years. Approximately 1,000 knitgood workers in Cleveland were organized into four locals comprising the Cleveland Knitgoods Council. This Council was supervised by the head of the Cleveland Joint Board. During the early 1950s, Louis Friend managed the Joint Board, and Nicholas Kirtzman was the director of the Cleveland and Ohio-Kentucky Region.
A new headquarters for the Cleveland ILGWU Health Center and Ohio-Kentucky regional headquarters was dedicated in 1951. David Solomon manager of the Joint Board for many years after Friend, retired April 1956, and the organizer of the Joint Board, Julius Guralnik, took over duties as manager of the Cleveland Joint Board. From 1959 into the 1960s, with the Cleveland cloak market declining into insignificance, a shift in the Ohio-Kentucky Region took place from an emphasis on the cloak industry towards sportswear, knitgoods, and dresses. The Cleveland Knitgoods Council made significant membership gains. By 1962, Kirtzman became director and manager of the Joint Board, with Edward Milano the assistant director, and the steady decline in membership in Cleveland within the shrinking cloak and dress industry began to stabilize.
Kirtzman, an ILGWU vice-president and regional director since 1950, died in March 1963. Sam Janis, who was previously an assistant general manager of the Eastern Region, succeeded Kirtzman as the new Ohio-Kentucky Region director and was also elected manager of the Cleveland Joint Board. In 1968, Janis and the Joint Board were involved in the successful campaign for Carl Stokes election as mayor of Cleveland. Stokes was the first African American mayor of a large U.S. city, and Manager Janis was appointed to the mayor's commission as a labor representative to study the welfare crisis in the city. During the 1970s, the Joint Board was involved in community and political activities, including submitting a proposal to ease procedures for voter registration.
In 1978, there was a realignment of the Ohio-Kentucky Region and all Ohio locals became part of the Northeast and Western Pennsylvania Department, renamed the Northeast, Western Pennsylvania and Ohio Department. Sam Janis retired in May 1978 and Al Gargiulo, who had been the assistant regional director, became the manager of the Cleveland Joint Board, as well as the Knitgoods Council and the Ohio District.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Cleveland Joint Board mainly consist of subject files arranged alphabetically. The subjects reflect the interest and activity of the Joint Board within the community. Topics covered include: Amun Israeli Housing and the campaign drive in Cleveland to raise funds including a luncheon with Dubinsky; community and local religious groups in Cleveland; fund contributions (for the war) by shops and members; the Italian American Labor Council; seeking funds and donations for health organizations such as the Los Angeles Sanatorium and Ex-Patients Home, the Jew Consumptive and Ex-Patients Relief Association, City of Hope and the Jewish Orthodox Old Home (support organization); letters and postcard from members currently in the military, often thanking the union for the care packages sent; monetary collections from members for war relief; and letters from orphans in Europe that the Joint Board "adopted."
In addition to community and good will activities, the collection also focuses on the Joint Board and its work within the garment industry in Cleveland. There is organizing material for various plants such as the Bloomfield Co., which includes leaflets, newsletters and election material; the BVD non-union unfair campaign; Keller Kohn and price lists, agreements, wage adjustments, the strike following the lockout (photos); and notice for shop meetings, wage comparisons for companies like Kleinman Cloak Co. There is information on manufacturing associations such as the Cleveland Apparel Manufacturers Association which represented various firms in negotiations and contract agreements with the Joint Board, the Cleveland Dress Manufacturers Association, and the Cleveland Embroidery Manufacturers Association, as well as firms with government contracts and the knit good industry. Also, a report compiled in 1941 includes charts, graphs and tables illustrating the cost of living, hours worked, hourly wages and total pay for operators, pressers, etc. within the Cleveland Cloak industry. But the collection also contains material on other regions and locals including Chicago and Cincinnati.
Groups and organizations are represented in the collection including the C.I.O., Cleveland Federation of Labor, and Jewish Labor Committee. There is also documents relating to the ILGWU such as informational material produced by the Educational Department, as well as information on classes, lectures offered, activity reports, and programs for shows and parties. There is correspondence with local representatives and congressmen, hand written meeting minutes, submissions for the publication "Justice" to editor Max Danish, and meeting notices for locals under the Joint Board.
Locals 26 (Cloak and Suit Tailors), Local 27 (Dress and Skirt Makers), Local 29 (Women Garment Makers), Local 37 (Cloak and Dress Pressers), Local 42 (Cloak and Dress Cutters), Local 44 (Italian Cloak & Dress Makers), Local 52 Embroidery Workers, Local 209 (Cotton Goods Local), Local 211 (Alteration Local), Local 295 (Knit Goods Workers Local), Local 326 (Cotton Dress Garment Local)
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/174: ILGWU. Cleveland Office records 5780/183: ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region records 5780/183 AV: ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region audio-visual materials 5780/183 P: ILGWU. Ohio Kentucky Region photographs
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- Ohio -- Cleveland; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Ohio -- Cleveland; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- Ohio -- Cleveland; Industrial relations -- United States; Industrial relations -- Ohio -- Cleveland; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- Cleveland Joint Board (Cleveland (Ohio)).
5490712
- American Federation of Labor, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Labor Party, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Amun-Israeli Housing Corp., 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- B, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Incl. Union's response to Brookings Institute survey of garment industry, 1945.
- The Bloomfield Co. [folder 1 of 2], 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Incl. organizing circulars & related printed material.
- The Bloomfield Co. [folder 2 of 2], 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bogen Silk Underwear Co., 1939-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brandeis, Louis D., Colony in Palestine, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- B.V.D. Co. [folder 1 of 2], 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Organizing campaign.
- B.V.D. Co. [folder 2 of 2], 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- C, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Cashmere Corp. of America, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chattanooga, Tenn., 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Ltrs. from John S. Martin.
- Chicago Jt. Bd., 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cincinnati, O, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Expenses for various shops on strike; expense account summaries.
- Cleveland Apparel Manufacturers Association [folder 1 of 2], 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cleveland Apparel Manufacturers Association [folder 2 of 2], 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cleveland Dress Manufacturers Association, 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Cleveland Embroidery Manufacturers Association, 1938-1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cleveland Federation of Labor, 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Committee for the Nation's Health, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Incl. Nicholas Kirtzman statement to the President's Commission on the Health of the Nation.
- Community Fund War Chest, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Congress of Industrial Organizations (Ohio) [folder 1 of 2], 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Congress of Industrial Organizations (Ohio) [folder 2 of 2], 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Conventions, Union, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Corrigan, William J., 1939-1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Legal advisor for Union.
- D, 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Education [folder 1 of 2], 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Union and non-union material
- Education [folder 2 of 2], 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Elyria Branch, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- F, 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Incl. ltrs. to Louis Friend.
- Famous Dress Co., 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Form Letters, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Freie Arbeiter Stimme, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- G, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Gottfried Co., 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Government, 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Corres. with members of all government branches.
- Haas and Bernstein Co., 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Haskel, Hannah, 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Huntington, W. Va., 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- I, 1939-1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Impartial Chairman, 1942-1946 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- ILGWU Campaign Committee, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Israel, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- J, 1940-1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Jewish Consumptive and Ex-Patients' Relief Association, 1939-1945 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Incl. Los Angeles Sanatorium, City of Hope.
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1940-1955 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Johnny Sportswear Mfg. Co., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Joint Board Minutes, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Misc.
- Justice, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Reports of activities submitted to Justice.
- K, 1942-1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Incl. Abraham Katovsky.
- Keller-Kohn Co., Inc. [folder 1 of 3], 1939-1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Keller-Kohn Co., Inc. [folder 2 of 3], 1939-1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Keller-Kohn Co., Inc. [folder 3 of 3], 1939-1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Kleinman Cloak Co., 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Knitted Outerwear Industry, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- L, 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Lampl Sportswear Manufacturing Co., 1941-1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Lewis Knitting Mills, 1941-1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Lieberman, Elias, 1939-1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Locals 26 and 29, 1942-1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Local 37, 1941-1945 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Local 63, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  I.c.w. David Solomon.
- Local 42, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Local 67, Toledo, O [folder 1 of 2], 1939-1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Local 67, Toledo, O [folder 2 of 2], 1939-1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Local 175, Conneaut, O., 1934-1942 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Local 175, 1945-1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Local 175, 1945-1953 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Lingerie Workers Local 175, 1945-1953 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Locals 200, 207 and 211, 1934-1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Local 368, 466, Toledo, O., 1942-1956 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Locals, Miscellaneous, 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Locals, Miscellaneous (outside of Ohio), 1940-1951 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- L.N. Gross Co., 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- L.N. Gross Co., 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Los Angeles Jt. Bd., 1939-1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- M, 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Members in Armed Services, 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Miller Cloak Shop, 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Miss Mode Co., 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- N, 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- National Committee for Labor Israel -Histadrut, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- National Labor Relations Board, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Incl. hearings of cases.
- The Nubone Company, Inc., Erie, Pa., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- 0, 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Incl. resolutions submitted to Ohio State Federation of Labor.
- Office of Price Administration, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Ohio Apparel Manufacturers Association and ILGWU, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Hearing for the consideration of amendments or modifications of agreement.
- Ohio Wesleyan University, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Talk delivered by N. Kirtzman.
- One Dollar and Twenty-Five Cents-Minimum Wage, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Orphans Adopted by ILGWU, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- P, 1940-1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Philadelphia Joint Board, 1940-1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- The Pollack-Altman Co., 1941-1948 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- The Printz-Biederman Co., 1934-1953 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- The Printz-Biederman Co., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Quality Manufacturing Co., Point Pleasant, W.Va., 1945-1950 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- R, 1941-1954 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Incl. resolutions.
- Research Department, 1941-1946 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Richmond, Ind., 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Ritmor Sportswear Co., 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Rosenfeld, William H., 1944-1953 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Rudolph Stern Dress Co., Inc., 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Rudolph Stern Dress Co., Inc., 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- S, 1941-1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Sicherman, George S., Inc., 1941-1946 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Solomon, Nathan, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Speeches and Statements, 1939-1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Statistical Data, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Nov. 1941. Charts and tables, Cleveland Cloak Industry.
- T, 1940-1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Incl. Toledo Garment Co.
- U, 1940-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- U.S. Labor Department, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Urban League, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- W, 1939-1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- War Relief Agencies, 1940-1949 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Collections of money during World War II for relief.